Guide to the Birge Malcolm Clark Papers, 1914-1985
Department of Special Collections
Birge Malcolm Clark Papers,
1914-1985
Special Collections M0627
Clark, Birge M. (Birge Malcolm), 1893-
5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of the Clark family, 1990
Biography
Palo Alto architect. Received his AB from Stanford in 1914 and B.Arch. from Columbia in 1917. Served as advising architect on the Lou Henry Hoover house and created numerous distinctive public buildings and private homes in Palo Alto.
Scope and Content
Class records and memorabilia, 1914, design notebook from Columbia, 1915, correspondence, 1983-1985, Historical Society material and class and subject files.
Access terms
Palo Alto Historical Society.; Stanford University--Curricula.; Architecture.; Buildings--Palo Alto (Calif.); Lou Henry Hoover House (Stanford, Calif.)
Container List
- Class of 1914 Records (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Class of 1914 Records (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Class of 1914 Records (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Class of 1914 Records (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Class of 1914 Records (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Birge M. Clark Half Century Club Ad Hoc 1975-1978 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Senior Center Talk March 1981 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Stanford Historical Society (1) (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Stanford Historical Society (2) (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Stanford Historical Society (3) (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Stanford Historical Society (4) (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Birge Clark 1982 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Birge Clark 1982 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Birge Clark 1982 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Correspondence (1) 1984 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Correspondence (2) 1984 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Correspondence 1983 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Corporation (Box 4, Folder 1)
- American Legion (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Class of 1914 - Agent 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Class of 1914 - Agent 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- History Copies 2 Types (Box 4, Folder 5)
- History 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- History Com (Box 4, Folder 7)
- History 1978 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Historical Society (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Historical Society (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Historical Society (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Connecticut Historical Society (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Historical Resources BD 1984 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Balloon Corps (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Balloon Corps (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Correspondence 1985 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Writings and Essays (1) 1985 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Writings and Essays (2) 1985 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Writings and Essays (3) 1985 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Writings and Essays (4) 1985 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Memorabilia 1914 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Miscellaneous (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Design notebook - Columbia 1915 (Box 8, Folder 1)